A Guide to the Keep Loudoun Beautiful, 1969-
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Keep Loudoun Beautiful, 1969-
Thomas Balch Library
M 052
The collection contains the records of Keep Loudoun Beautiful including minutes, correspondence, newspaper articles, projects, photographs, and scrapbooks from1969-2006.
Keep Loudoun Beautiful
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Keep Loudoun Beautiful, Loudoun County, VA.
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
2006.0086, 2006.0192
Historical Information
Loudoun County resident Agnes Harrison headed efforts to fight the county's litter problem in the late 1960s. She founded Keep Loudoun Beautiful (KLB), as a volunteer organization to help combat litter and reduce pollution; it incorporated 30 March 1972. In a dramatic gesture, Harrison and other early leaders expressed their concern to county officials by gathering roadside trash and depositing it on the Board of Supervisor's conference room floor.
At present, KLB's mission includes maintaining the county's natural beauty, promoting public awareness of environmental issues, improving trash disposal and eliminating illegal dumping. Among other activities, KLB coordinates a yearly "Spring Cleanup" program to organize volunteers to pick up trash along roads, waterways, and other public areas in the county.
Scope and Content
The collection contains the records of Keep Loudoun Beautiful. It includes minutes, correspondence, newspaper articles, projects, photographs, and scrapbooks from 1969-2006. Images are individually catalogued in PastPerfect, Thomas Balch Library's visual collections database available onsite, and may be identified in the online index available at www.leesburgva.gov/ThomasBalchLibrary/SpecialCollections by searching vc_0034. This is an open collection.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Keep Loudoun Beautiful (M 052), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Keep Loudoun Beautiful, http://keeploudounbeautiful.org/index.html(accessed 26 August 2010).
Other Finding Aid
Past Perfect catalogue records for photographs.
Technical Requirements
None
Related Material
None
Contents List
- (Box 1)
  - Bylaws, n.d.
  - Board of Directors, n.d.
  - Membership, n.d.
  - Committee Assignments, n.d.
  - Minutes, 1969-1970
  - Minutes, 1971
  - Minutes, 1972
  - Minutes, 1973
  - Minutes, 1974
  - Minutes, 1975
  - Minutes, 1976
  - Minutes, 1977
  - Minutes, 1978
  - Minutes, 1979
  - Minutes, 1980
  - Minutes, 1981
  - Minutes, 1982
  - Minutes, 1983
  - Minutes, 1984
  - Minutes, 1985
  - Minutes, 1986
  - Minutes, 1987
- (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1988
  - Minutes, 1989
  - Minutes, 1990
  - Minutes, 1991
  - Minutes, 1992
  - Minutes, 1993
  - Minutes, 1994
  - Minutes, 1995
  - Minutes, 1996
  - Minutes, 1997
  - Minutes, 1998
  - Minutes, 1999
  - Minutes, 2000
  - Minutes, 2001
  - Minutes, 2002
  - Minutes, 2003
  - Minutes, 2004
  - Minutes, 2005
  - Minutes, 2006
  - Directors Ballots, n.d.
- (Box 3)
  - Reports, n.d.
  - Annual Meeting Invitations, n.d.
  - Correspondence: Mrs. Gustav (Mercedes) Eyssell, n.d.
  - Correspondence: Agnes Harrison, n.d.
  - Correspondence: William Harrison, n.d.
  - Correspondence: G. A. Horkan Jr., n.d.
  - Correspondence: Norma Netherwood, n.d.
  - Correspondence: Peter Packard, n.d.
  - Correspondence: Shirley Pearson, n.d.
  - Correspondence: Mrs. C. Russell Taylor, n.d.
  - Correspondence, 1960s
  - Correspondence, 1970-1989
  - Correspondence, 1990-2006
  - Contest Calendars, 1995, 1997-2001
- (Box 4)
  - Jason Memorial Garden, n.d.
  - Children's Beautification and Clean-up Projects: Troop 970, n.d.
  - Children's Beautification and Clean-up Projects: Round Hill Elementary School, n.d.
  - Bottle Bill, n.d.
  - Spring Clean-up: Kick-off Luncheon Invitations and Programs, n.d.
  - Spring Clean-up, 1970s
  - Spring Clean-up, 1980-1982
  - Spring Clean-up, 1983-1985
  - Spring Clean-up, 1986-1989
  - Spring Clean-up, 1990s
  - Spring Clean-up, 2000s
- (Box 5)
  - Newsletters, n.d.
  - News Articles, 1970s
  - News Articles, 1980-1987
  - News Articles, 1988
  - News Articles, 1990s
  - Landfill Project: Scrapbook, 1970-1972
  - Spring Clean-up 1971: Scrapbook, 1970-1972
  - Education: Scrapbook, 1970-1972
  - Scrapbook: Organization, Cooperation, Unique Aspects, 1970-1972
  - Businesses and Other Groups, Accomplishments: Scrapbook, 1970-1972
  - Spring Clean-up 1972: Scrapbook, 1970-1972
  - Documentation & Summary of Achievements, Current Status, Future Plans: Scrapbook, 1970-1972
  - Goals and Objectives: Scrapbook, 1972-1973
  - Business: Scrapbook, 1972-1973
  - Scrapbook: Labor, 1972-1973
  - Scrapbook: Youth, 1972-1973
- (Box 6)
  - Government: Scrapbook, 1972-1973
  - Citizen Involvement: Scrapbook, 1972-1973
  - Litter Prevention Projects: Scrapbook, 1972-1973
  - Spring Clean-up: Scrapbook, 1972-1973
  - Documentation: Scrapbook, 1972-1973
  - Scrapbook: Achievements and Future Plans, 1972-1973
  - Scrapbook: Leadership and Membership, 1979-1980
  - Scrapbook: Recycling, 1979-1980
  - Clean-up: Scrapbook, 1979-1980
  - Scrapbook: Enforcement, Education, 1979-1980
  - Scrapbook: Publicity, Litter Control, Bottle Bill, 1979-1980
  - Scrapbook: Aims/Activities, Leadership, 1981-1982
  - Scrapbook: Membership, Clean-up, 1981-1982
  - Scrapbook: Recycling, Speaker's Bureau, Education, 1981-1982
  - Scrapbook: Legislation, 1981-1982
  - Scrapbook: Purpose, Organization, Leadership, Membership, KaLeB, 1981-1982
  - Scrapbook: Clean-up, 1981-1982
  - Scrapbook: Education, Recycling, Legislation, 1981-1982
- (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook 1981-1982: Special Events, 1981-1982
  - Scrapbook, 1985
  - Negatives, n.d.
  - Photograph Captions and Identification, n.d.
  - Miscellaneous, n.d.
  - Memorabilia: button, n.d.
- (Box 8)
  - Scrapbooks, 1976-1994
- (Box 9)
  - Scrapbooks, 1994-2002
- (VC 0034)
  - Photographs: Spring Clean-up - Troop 2130, 1982
  - Photographs, 1982
  - Photographs, 1988, 1990
  - Photographs, 1996-1998
  - Photographs, n.d.
  - Photographs, n.d.
  - Photographs, n.d.
  - Photographs: Camp Fire Boys and Girls of Loudoun County, n.d.